A Guide to the University of Virginia Division of Continuing Education, General Records, Office of the Dean, 1925-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Division of Continuing Education, General Records, Office of the Dean 1925-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-16/1/6.771
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was an archival transfer from the Division of Continuing Education, 1977 July 11.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of general records from the Office of the Dean, Division of Continuing Education, including correspondence and related papers on University officials, the committee on extension courses, extension expansion, future directions, and legislation.
Arrangement
The reocrds are arranged alphabetically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Biology Building (old "stiff hall") Continuing Education, School of- Eastern Shore Branch Continuing Education, School of- Madison Center Continuing Education, School of- Northern Virginia Center Continuing Education, School of- Roanoke Center Continuing Education, School of- Quantico Center (FBI) Continuing Education, School of- Miscellaneous
Frank Bane James C. Bardin Abraham Berglund John Canady Mary Crowley Henry H. Cumming Andre C. DePorry Atcheson L. Hench Hoxton Linwood Lehman Charles G. Maphis Mitchell C. H. Morrissette G. G. Peery George Zehmer
E. R. Combs L. G. Moffatt H. B. Pearson Nathaniel Peffer George E. Vincent E. G. William
Contents List
- Abingdon Program, 1963 (Folder 1)
- Adult Basic Education, ca. 1971 (Folder 1)
- Adult Education- Historical Development in Virginia and Southeastern States, 1937-1958 (Folder 1)
- Agreements- Northern Virginia, 1970-1972 (Folder 1)
- Alderman, E. A. (Office of the President) Correspondence with George B. Zehmer, 1925-1927 (Folder 1)
- Alumni Institute, 1959-1961 (Folder 1)
- Application for Purchase of Real Property with Public Benefit Allowance Discount, 1961 (Folder 1)
- Applications for Jobs with UVA Extension, 1955-1958, 1970, 1970- 1 item. (Folder 1)
- Associate Provost for Research, 1972 (Folder 1)
- Bills and Resolutions- Virginia General Assembly, 1972 (Folder 1)
- Bryant, M. Howard, 1959 (Folder 1)
- Budget Request, 1965 (Folder 1)
- Building Program- Madison Field Office, 1965-1966 (Folder 1)
- Business Office, 1970-1973, 2 folders. (Folder 1)
- Capital Outlay Requests, 1968 (Folder 1)
- Center for Continuing Education- Northern Virginia, 1971-1975 (Folder 1)
- Certificate Programs, 1971 (Folder 1)
- Clinch Valley College, 1955-1962 (Folder 1)
- Cole, James W., Jr., 1958-1968 (Folder 1)
- Committee (Ad Hoc) on Coordination of Continuing Education for Nurses, MCV-VCU, 1971 (Folder 1)
- Committee on Extension Activities- Master of General Studies Degree, 1969-1971 (Folder 2)
- Committee on Extension Courses, 1955-1957 (Folder 2)
- Committee on Future of the University, 1972 (Folder 2)
- Comptroller, 1971-1972 (Folder 2)
- Conferences and Institutes, 1970 (Folder 2)
- Consortium- Northern Virginia, 1972-1974 (Folder 2)
- Consortium- State Council of Higher Education, 1970-1972 (Folder 2)
- Consumer Health Education Project, 1971-1972 (Folder 2)
- Continuing Education Building, 1971-1972 (Folder 2)
- Continuing Education for Nurses, 1972 (Folder 2)
- Continuing Education Unit, 1970-1972 (Folder 2)
- Correspondence- Northern Virginia, 1966-1972 (Folder 2)
- Correspondence Course- Feasibility, 1923-1935, 2 folders. (Folder 2)
- Crawford, Edwin M.- Vice President for Public Affairs, 1971-1972 (Folder 2)
- Crockett, S. R.- Confidential File, 1961-1967 (Folder 3)
- Darden, Jr., C. W. (Office of the President), Correspondence with George B. Zehmer, 1944-1954, 2 folders. (Folder 3)
- de Porry, Andre, (Director of Lynchburg Extension Center) re Lynchburg Center, 1957-1958 (Folder 3)
- de Porry, Andre- Speeches and Reports, 1959-1976 (Folder 3)
- Eastern Shore Branch- Building Program, 1963-1971 (Folder 3)
- Education Coordinator's Report- Building Program, 1964-1965 (Folder 3)
- Education Extension- Dr. Busse, 1965 (Folder 4)
- Education, School of, 1970-1971 (Folder 4)
- Engineering (Undergraduate), 1972-1973 (Folder 4)
- Expansion of Extension Centers- Clifton Forge, 1961 (Folder 4)
- Expansion of Extension Centers- Lynchburg, 1961 (Folder 4)
- Extension and Public Service Advisory Committee, 1972 March 29 (Folder 4)
- Extension Topics, 1926-1931 (Folder 4)
- Extension Work- General, 1939, 1954, n.d. (Folder 4)
- Faculty Meetings re Branch and Extension Work, 1952-1961 (Folder 4)
- F. B. I. Academy at Quantico, 1971-1973, 2 folders. (Folder 4)
- F. B. I. National Academy, 1970-1971 (Folder 4)
- Fort Belvoir Agreement, 1970-1971 (Folder 4)
- Future Directions for the School of General Studies, 1970 (Folder 4)
- General Assembly Action Affecting School of General Studies, 1966 (Folder 4)
- George Mason College and Northern Virginia Center for Continuing Education, 1966-1972 (Folder 4)
- Graduate School of Business- Policy Statement, 1969 (Folder 4)
- Graduate Programs- Off-Grounds, 1966, 1970 (Folder 4)
- Hampton Roads Center, 1971-1972 (Folder 4)
- Home Reading Courses, 1927-1928 (Folder 4)
- Information Services, (William H. Fishback, Jr.), 1971 (Folder 4)
- James Monroe Law Office, Museum and Memorial Library, 1964-1968 (Folder 4)
- James Monroe Museum Library, 1964-1972 (Folder 5)
- Law Enforcement, 1968-1969 (Folder 5)
- Legislation- Community College, 1966-1967 (Folder 5)
- Lynchburg Center, 1948-1953, 1960-1961 (Folder 5)
- Madison County Extension Center, 1962-1969, 1972-1973 (Folder 5)
- Mary Washington College, 1972-1975 (Folder 6)
- Mozart Music Festival- Correspondence, notes, schedules, recorded executive meetings, (Mr. Franklin Bacon, Jr. of Continuing Education Involved), 1951 February- June (Folder 6)
- National University Extension Association- Dues, 1970-1971 (Folder 6)
- National University Extension Association- Region III Annual Meeting, 1971 March (Folder 6)
- Newcomb, J. H. (Office of the President), Correspondence with George B. Zehmer, 1934-1944 (Folder 6)
- Newsletters, 1962, 1969, 1972 (Folder 6)
- Northern Virginia Extension Center, 1959-1960, 1965-1973, 2 folders. (Folder 6)
- Nursing Programs- Initiation and Coordination, 1964-1973 (Folder 6)
- Ogden, Jesse, and Jean, 1957 (Folder 6)
- Patrick Henry College, 1962-1971, 3 folders. (Folder 7)
- Patrick Henry College- Adams, Hazel Ruth, 1962 (Folder 7)
- Photographs, Correspondence re, ca. 1920-1945 (Folder 7)
- Planning Districts, 1971 (Folder 7)
- Press Releases, 1965-1966 (Folder 7)
- Proposal-Putting Research in Adult Basic Education, 1971 (Folder 7)
- Proposed Extension Center- Madison, 1960-1962 (Folder 7)
- Proposed Policy Statement re Federal Grants, n.d. (Folder 7)
- Provost's Office, (Mr. Frank L. Hereford, Jr.), 1970-1971 (Folder 7)
- Provost, Assistant, 1971-1972 (Folder 7)
- Provost's Office, 1972-1973 (Folder 7)
- Provost for Research, 1971-1972 (Folder 7)
- Provost for Research (Associate- State Institute), 1971 (Folder 7)
- Radio- Television, 1973 (Folder 7)
- Red Cross Building, 1971-1972 (Folder 7)
- Report- School of General Studies, 1961-1972 (Folder 7)
- Reports re School and Community Drama, 1942-1944 (Folder 7)
- Richmond Center, Dr. John M. Dunnavant, 1970-1971 (Folder 8)
- Roanoke Center, 1966 (Folder 8)
- Roanoke Center- Crockett, Samuel R., Director, 1962-1966, 2 folders. (Folder 8)
- Roanoke Center- Norfolk and Western Railway Company, 1973 (Folder 8)
- Roanoke Center- Planning Programs and Architects, 1965-1966 (Folder 8)
- Roanoke Center- Statistics and Justifications, 1965-1966 (Folder 8)
- Roanoke Project, 1965-1966 (Folder 8)
- Roanoke Regional Center, 1971-1973 (Folder 8)
- Roanoke Regional Office, 1962-1973 (Folder 8)
- Roanoke Regional Office, Mr. John D. Murdaugh, 1970-1972 (Folder 8)
- Saunier, Paul, 1971 (Folder 8)
- School of Continuing Education- Functions and Activities, 1972-1973 (Folder 8)
- Self-Study Committee, 1970, 1973 (Folder 8)
- Senate Joint Resolution, 1970 (Folder 8)
- Shannon, Edgar F. (Office of the President)- Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Folder 8)
- Shannon, Edgar (Office of the President) Correspondence with Andre C. de Porry, 1970-1972 (Folder 9)
- Shea, Vincent, vice President for Business and Finance, 1970-1972, 2 folders. (Folder 9)
- Southern Association, 1971-1972 (Folder 9)
- Southern Association Report, 1970 (Folder 9)
- Southern Association for Colleges and Schools, 1970 (Folder 9)
- Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1971-1972 (Folder 9)
- Southwestern Virginia Center- Mr. Curtis L. Ramsey, 1970-1971 (Folder 9)
- Special Students, 1969-1972, 2 folders. (Folder 9)
- Speeches- Dean de Porry, 1960-1972 (Folder 9)
- Standard Nine, 1971-1972 (Folder 9)
- Standard Nine- Off-Grounds Degree Programs, 1972 (Folder 9)
- Standard Ten, 1969 (Folder 9)
- Standard Ten- Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1969, 1972 (Folder 9)
- State Board of Eduction- Dr. A. Gordon Brooks, 1971 (Folder 9)
- State Council of Higher Education- Extension and Public Service Committee, 1966, 1967, 1970 (Folder 9)
- State Council of Higher Educcation- Dr. Roy E. McTarnaghan, 1970-1972 (Folder 9)
- State Council of Higher Education- Dr. Daniel E. Marvin, Jr., 1969-1973, 3 folders. (Folder 9)
- State Council of Higher Education- Micellaneous, 1966-1972 (Folder 9)
- State Council of Higher Education- Regional Councils, 1970-1972 (Folder 9)
- State Department of Education, 1971-1972 (Folder 9)
- State Division of Planning and Community Services, 1971-1973 (Folder 10)
- Student Council- Transfer Credit, 1966 (Folder 10)
- Summary- Offerings of the School of General Studies, 1969 (Folder 10)
- Survey of Extension, 1968 (Folder 10)
- Tentative Proposal for a Comprehensive Study Continuing Education, n.d. (Folder 10)
- Tidewater Council for Continuing Education, 1968, 1971, n.d., 2 folders. (Folder 10)
- Title I, 1965, 1968-1970, 1972 (Folder 10)
- University Branch Colleges- Establishment, 1950-1954 (Folder 10)
- University Senate, 1971, 1972 (Folder 10)
- University of Virginia Center for Continuing Education- Justification to offer Lower Division Courses, 1970-1971 (Folder 10)
- University of Virginia Newsletter, 1959 (Folder 10)
- Vice President for Student Affairs- D. Alan Williams, 1973 (Folder 10)
- Virginia Advisory Legislative Council, 1969-1972 (Folder 10)
- Virginia Department of Community Colleges- Eastern Shore Branch, 1966, 1971 (Folder 10)
- Virginia State Planning Districts, 1972 (Folder 10)
- Wallops Station Apprentice Program and Technical Training Requirements, 1963 (Folder 10)
- Wise County Project, 1972 (Folder 10)
- Zehmer, George B.- Articles, 1934-1935, 1944, 1957-1958 (Folder 10)
- Zehmer, George B.- Biography, 1961 (Folder 10)
- Micellaneous, 1938-1965 (Folder 10)